Galaxy Conference Records
Galaxy Conference Records
1967-1970
Galaxy Conference on Adult Education (1969: Washington, D.C.)
1.5 linear ft.
The Galaxy Conference on Adult Education was held in Washington, D.C. in 1969. Participating organizations included the American Education Association, American Library Association, Commission of Professors of Adult Education, Committee of Adult Education Organizations, Council of National Organizations, National Association for Public School Adult Education, National Council on Adult Jewish Education, and the National University Extension Association. The records of the Galaxy Conference provide comprehensive documentation of the history, planning and execution of the conference.
148994
Biographical History
The Galaxy Conference of Adult. Education Organizations was held in Washington, D.C., in 1969. It was the outgrowth of the Conference of Adult Education Organizations, convened in 1964 to provide liaison among the major professional associations in the field and to focus on common concerns. By 1969, 19 organizations were participating. The Conference, which had both general sessions and associated conferences, was successful both in its own right and in forwarding the goals of the Committee of Adult Education Organizations, which dropped the ad hoc qualification and later incorporated as the Coalition of Adult Education Organizations (CAEO).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Galaxy Papers, besides giving a comprehensive documentation of the planning and execution of the Conference, include (in Box 3) an organized history, a formal report, and the statement "Imperatives for Action," which resulted from the Galaxy Conference.
Related Material
The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Additional material on the Wingspread Conference is located in the Council for the Continuing Education Unit (CCEU) Records. Other collections that may be of particular interest include:
Adult Education Association (AEA-USA)/American Association for Adult and Continuing Education (AAACE) Records
Association of University Evening Colleges (AUEC) Records
Alexander N. Charters papers
Coalition of Adult Education Organizations (CAEO) Records
Commission of the Professors of Adult Education (CPAE) Records
International Congress of University Adult Education (ICUAE) Records
National Association for Public School Adult Educators (NAPSAE) Records
National University Extension Association (NUEA) Records
University Council on Education for Public Responsibility (UCEPR) Records
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Charters, Alexander N.; Galaxy Conference on Adult Education (1969: Washington, D.C.); Adult education -- United States.; Evening and continuation schools -- United States.; Correspondence.; Reports.; Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Organizational papers
  - Advertising, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Budgets, correspondence re, 1967-1970 (Box 1)
  - Central Planning Group
    - 1964-1970 (Box 1)
    - 1968-1970 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, general, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Evaluation, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Exhibits, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Exhibits and advertising, correspondence re, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Local arrangements, 1969 (Box 1)
  - News releases, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Program committee, 1968-1970 (Box 2)
  - Program materials, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Program materials and papers, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Program schedules, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Public relations, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Registration packet information, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Speakers, 1969 (Box 2)
- Participating organizations
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1967-1969 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, A-Z, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Adult Education Association, 1969 (Box 3)
  - American Library Association, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - Commission of the Professors of Adult Education, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Committee of Adult Education Organizations, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - Council of National Organizations, 1969 (Box 3)
  - National Association for Public School Adult Education, 1969 (Box 3)
  - National Council on Adult Jewish Education, 1969 (Box 3)
  - National University Extension Association, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous
  - Charters, Alexander N., 1969; notes (Box 3)
  - History of the planning for the conference, 1970 (Box 3)
  - "Imperatives for Action", 1969 (Box 3)
  - Report on the 1969 Galaxy Conference of Adult Education Organizations, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Wingspread Conference, 1969; general papers (Box 3)